Collection on P. T. Barnum MS002
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Loose prints, 1849 -- 1975; 1888 -- 1975; MS002.002; 0.0 Linear Feet; 43 Digital Object(s)
  This series contains loose photographic prints from the Barnum collection. Loose prints are stored separately from the collection.
  This series is arranged as found.
  - Barnum's Gallery of Wonders. No. 1./ General Tom Thumb, 1849; MS002.002.00001 (Box Large Map Case 3 Drawer 10)
    Color lithograph printed by N. Currier (of Currier & Ives). Gift of Robert Jones, Class of 1953.
  - P.T. Barnum as an older man, MS002.002.DO.00015 (Box Shared 143)
    Portraits; People; Phineas Taylor Barnum papers; photographic print; Barnum, P. T. (Phineas Taylor); Board of Trustees
  - Jumbo in front of the museum with unidentified man, 1927; MS002.002.DO.00018 (Box Shared 143)
    Buildings; Academic; Phineas Taylor Barnum papers; photographic print; Jumbo
  - Jumbo, Doris Vaughn Blaisdell (J1923) and an unidentified Jackson student stand by Jumbo, 1922; MS002.002.DO.00020 (Box Shared 83)
    People; Students; Phineas Taylor Barnum papers; photographic print; Jumbo; Blaisdell, Doris Vaughn
  - Russell Carpenter Jr. age 10, with Jumbo during reconstruction, 1942; MS002.002.DO.00021 (Box Shared 83)
    People; Phineas Taylor Barnum papers; photographic print; Jumbo
  - Unidentified Barnum family members with P.T. Barnum, MS002.002.DO.00022
    Portraits; Phineas Taylor Barnum papers; Barnum, P. T. (Phineas Taylor)
  - Jenny Lind, MS002.002.DO.00023 (Box Shared 143)
    cabinet card
    Portraits; Phineas Taylor Barnum papers; Lind, Jenny
  - Younger Barnum sitting in chair, MS002.002.DO.00039 (Box Shared 142)
    Portraits; Phineas Taylor Barnum papers; cartes-de-visite; Barnum, P. T. (Phineas Taylor); Board of Trustees
  - Barnum in a top hat, MS002.002.DO.00040 (Box Shared 143)
    Portraits; Phineas Taylor Barnum papers; photographic print; Barnum, P. T. (Phineas Taylor); Board of Trustees
  - Older Barnum in glasses, MS002.002.DO.00041 (Box Shared 143)
  - Younger Barnum, MS002.002.DO.00042 (Box Shared 142)
  - Middle-aged Barnum, MS002.002.DO.00043 (Box Shared 142, Box Shared 143)
    Portraits; Phineas Taylor Barnum papers; photographic print; copy negative; Barnum, P. T. (Phineas Taylor); Board of Trustees
  - Borneo brothers from Barnum Circus, 1880; MS002.002.DO.00044 (Box Shared 143)
    cabinet card; This date is approximate
    People; Phineas Taylor Barnum papers
  - Jumbo being fed by a policeman, 1882; MS002.002.DO.00045; Unknown; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 117)
    People; Phineas Taylor Barnum papers; copy negative; Jumbo
  - Stuffed Jumbo next to elephant skeleton, MS002.002.DO.00046 (Box Shared 142)
    2 copies
    Phineas Taylor Barnum papers; photographic print; Jumbo
  - Barnum Hall, 1925; MS002.002.DO.00047 (Box Shared 143)
    Buildings; Academic; Phineas Taylor Barnum papers; photographic print
  - Russell L. Carpenter in lab coat with unidentified worker who is cleaning Jumbo during restoration, 1942; MS002.002.DO.00048 (Box Shared 142)
  - Jumbo with Joan Franceschini Whittaker (far right) and three other unidentified students, 1933; MS002.002.DO.00049 (Box Shared 142, Box Shared 143)
    People; Students; Phineas Taylor Barnum papers; photographic print; photographic print; Jumbo
  - Russell L. Carpenter in lab coat and unidentified worker during Jumbo restoration, 1942; MS002.002.DO.00050 (Box Shared 143)
  - Russell L. Carpenter in lab coat and unidentified workers during Jumbo restoration, 1942; MS002.002.DO.00051 (Box Shared 142, Box Shared 143)
    People; Phineas Taylor Barnum papers; photographic print; copy negative; Jumbo
  - Jumbo restoration, 1942; MS002.002.DO.00052 (Box Shared 142)
  - Jumbo restoration, 1942; MS002.002.DO.00053 (Box Shared 142)
  - Jumbo restoration, 1942; MS002.002.DO.00054 (Box Shared 142)
  - Jumbo with circus performer, MS002.002.DO.00055 (Box Shared 142)
  - Jumbo with students sitting at a table, 1948; MS002.002.DO.00056 (Box Shared 142)
    Students are: standing l-r: Ernest Harmon, Edmund Johnson, Jr., Priscilla Peirce, and Richard Cooke; seated, Muriel Manson, Mildred Listernick, Martha Henderson, and Lena Kofos.
    People; Students; Phineas Taylor Barnum papers; photographic print; Jumbo; Harmon, Ernest; Johnson, Edmund, Jr.; Peirce, Priscilla; Cooke, Richard; Manson, Muriel; Listernick, Mildred; Henderson, Martha; Komidar, Joseph
  - Construction of the Barnum Museum, 1886; MS002.002.DO.00057; Unknown; Rollins, Edwin B. (Box Shared 142, Box Shared 143)
    Phineas Taylor Barnum papers; photographic print; copy negative
  - Construction of the Barnum Museum, 1886; MS002.002.DO.00058 (Box Shared 144)
    Phineas Taylor Barnum papers; photographic print
  - Barnum Museum (exterior), 1887; MS002.002.DO.00059 (Box Shared 144)
  - Barnum Museum (exterior), 1887; MS002.002.DO.00060 (Box Shared 144)
  - Tom Thumb and family, 1865; MS002.002.DO.00061 (Box Shared 143)
    cartes-de-visite; This date is approximate
    Phineas Taylor Barnum papers
  - Mr. and Mrs. Tom Thumb with best man and bridesmaid, 1863; MS002.002.DO.00062 (Box Shared 143)
  - Tom Thumb's wedding ceremony in church, 1863; MS002.002.DO.00063 (Box Shared 143)
  - Print of drawing of Jenny Lind by Chas H. Crosby & Co., n.d., MS002.002.DO.00064 (Box Shared 144)
    Phineas Taylor Barnum papers; photographic print; Lind, Jenny
  - Barnum Hall on fire, April 14, 1975; MS002.002.DO.00274; Baer, J.C. (Box Shared 86)
    Events; Buildings; Academic; Phineas Taylor Barnum papers; photographic print; Barnum, P. T. (Phineas Taylor)
  - Barnum Hall on fire, April 14, 1975; MS002.002.DO.00275; Baer, J.C. (Box Shared 86)
  - Barnum Hall on fire, April 14, 1975; MS002.002.DO.00276; Baer, J.C. (Box Shared 86)
  - Barnum Hall on fire, April 14, 1975; MS002.002.DO.00277; Baer, J.C. (Box Shared 86)
  - Barnum Hall on fire, April 14, 1975; MS002.002.DO.00278; Baer, J.C. (Box Shared 86)
  - Jumbo and Tom Thumb see the approaching train, 1885; MS002.002.DO.00322 (Box Shared 86)
    From a woodcut.
    Phineas Taylor Barnum papers; photographic print; Jumbo; Barnum, P. T. (Phineas Taylor)
  - Jumbo saving Tom Thumb., 1885; MS002.002.DO.00323 (Box Shared 86)
    From a woodcut
  - After the Accident, 1885; MS002.002.DO.00324 (Box Shared 86)
  - Jumbo's death, crowd scene, 1885; MS002.002.DO.00325 (Box Shared 85)
  - Jumbo's death, with trainer, 1885; MS002.002.DO.00326 (Box Shared 85)
  - Advertising card featuring Jumbo the elephant, 1885; MS002.002.DO.04436 (Box Shared 20)
    This date is approximate
    Elephants; People; Phineas Taylor Barnum papers; photographic print; Jumbo